<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<preface id="core.overview">
  <title>Overview</title>

  <para>The JDBC support in the Spring Framework is extensive and covers the
  most commonly used features, but there are some new usage scenarios like
  type-safe queries that warrants some extension to be provided. The core part
  of the <emphasis>Spring Data JDBC Extensions</emphasis> project provides
  this type of extension and it can be used together with any supported SQL
  database.</para>

  <section id="core.overview-whats-covered">
    <title>Features provided</title>

    <para>The following lists the various features that are covered. Each
    feature is documented in more detail in the following chapters</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
         Core support 

        <remark>The core support provides extensions to the Spring Framework
        JDBC support.</remark>

         
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
         Querydsl 

        <remark>The Querydsl project provides a way to work with many
        datastore in a type-safe manner. This includes support for working
        with SQL databases. We provide the "glue" that let's you easily work
        with Querydsl in a Spring based project.</remark>

         
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>

  <section id="core.requires">
    <title>Requirements</title>

    <para>The requirements for using the features provided in the
    <classname>core</classname> module of the "Spring Data JDBC Extensions"
    project are listed below.</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
         Java 6 or later 

        <remark>The minimum Java version is now 1.6.</remark>

         
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
         Spring Framework 3.0 

        <remark>All Spring Framework features that are needed are provided in
        Spring Framework version 3.0 or later.</remark>

         
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
         Apache Commons Logging 

        <remark>Apache Commons Logging is used by the Spring Framework but it
        can be replaced by the jcl-over-slf4j bridge provided by the SLF4J
        project.</remark>

         
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
         Querydsl 

        <remark>The Querydsl support requires the use of Querydsl SQL module
        version 3.0.0 or later (library is built using 3.3.0).</remark>

         
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
</preface>